As you probably have noticed, I put up here on my shared screen the part of the webpage.
Most of the class is driven from the schedule.
I'll talk a little bit later about it.
But, you know, hopefully you find the URL and you found the schedule.
I'll return to that a little bit later in more detail.
Okay.
So what's the plan for today?
So I'm going to talk a little bit about what is a distributed system.
So what is it?
And maybe give a little bit of historical context, you know, how distributed systems have developed over the last couple decades.
Then hit a little bit on the core structure, like what you should expect.
Then talk.
What are the main.
Topics or the main recurring topics that we'll see throughout the term.
And then we'll see actually first illustration of those main topics by the case study.
That was assigned for today, the paper MapReduce, which is also the topic of the first lap.
And you watch the Piazza, you know, we just posted that to the lab on Piazza URL so that you can get going.
And it's due next Friday.
So let's start with the basics.
I'll talk a little bit about what is a distributed system.
And sort of, you know, maybe easy to start with a little picture.
The internet, the cloud.
Yeah.
We have computers connected to clients and maybe servers.
Maybe you have servers.
You have servers that actually are complete data centers.
Clients.
And data centers themselves, you know, may be internally distributed systems that are connected by internal networks.
The data centers themselves might be internal connections, you know, outside of the internet.
But there's a large collection of computers connected by networks.
And, you know, sort of, you know, you can see that there's a lot of data centers that are connected by networks.
And, you know, sort of, informally, you know, the way I think about it, what a distributed system is, that there's a multiple, you know, more than one computer network.
You know, so they can interact only through, you know, sending or receiving packets.
As opposed to, say, a multiprocessor where you can interact through shared memory.
And they're cooperating, you know, to deliver some service.
So those are sort of the four keywords, you know, that define, you know, for me.
Distributed systems.